Hi, everyone, welcome back.
大家好，欢迎回来。
Today, I think that these two lectures today are really exciting,
今天，我认为今天的这两节课真的很令人兴奋，
because they start to move beyond,
因为它们开始超越，
you know, a lot of what we've talked about in the class so far,
到目前为止，我们在这门课上讲了很多东西，
which is focusing a lot on really static data sets
主要集中在非常静态的数据集上，
and specifically in today, in this lecture, right now,
特别是在今天，在这节课中，现在，
I'm going to start to talk about how we can learn about this very long standing field
我要开始谈论如何学习这个由来已久的领域，
of how we can specifically marry two topics.
我们如何特别地结合两个话题。
The first topic being reinforcement learning,
第一个主题是强化学习，
which has existed for many, many decades,
它已经存在了很多，几十年，
together with a lot of the very recent advances in deep learning,
还有很多深度学习的最新进展，
which you've already started learning about
作为这门课程的一部分，
as part of this course.
你们已经开始学习了。
Now this marriage of these two fields is actually really fascinating to me,
现在这两个领域的结合对我来说真的很吸引人，
particularly, because like I said,
特别是，因为就像我说的，
it moves away from this whole paradigm of
它背离了整个范例，
or really this whole paradigm that we've been exposed to in the class thus far,
或者说是我们到目前为止在课堂上接触到的整个范例，
and that paradigm is really how we can build a deep learning model using some data set,
这种模式就是我们可以使用一些数据集来构建深度学习模型的方式，
but that data set is typically fixed in in our world, right,
但这个数据集通常是固定在我们的世界里的，
we collect, we go out and go collect that data set,
我们收集，我们出去收集数据集，
we deploy it on our machine learning or deep learning algorithm
我们将其部署在我们的机器学习或深度学习算法上，
and then we can evaluate on a brand new data set,
然后我们可以在一个全新的数据集上进行评估，
but that is very different than the way things work in the real world,
但这与现实世界中的运作方式有很大不同，
in the real world,
在现实世界中，
you have your deep learning model actually deployed together with the data
你的深度学习模型实际上与数据一起部署在一起，
together, out into reality,
进入现实，
exploring, interacting with its environment
探索，与其环境互动，
and trying out a whole bunch of different actions and different things in that environment
并在该环境中尝试一大堆不同的行动和不同的事情，
in order to be able to learn
以便能够学习，
how to best perform any particular task that may need to accomplish,
如何最好地执行任何可能需要完成的特定任务，
and typically we want to be able to do this without explicit human supervision, right,
通常，我们希望能够在没有明确的人类监督的情况下做到这一点，
this is the key motivation of reinforcement learning,
这是强化学习的关键动机，
you're going to try and learn through reinforcement,
你将尝试通过强化来学习，
making mistakes in your world
在你的世界中犯错误，
and then collecting data on those mistakes to learn how to improve.
然后收集这些错误的数据来学习如何改进。
Now, this is obviously a huge field in or a huge topic in the field of robotics and autonomy,
这显然是机器人和自主领域的一个巨大的领域或一个巨大的主题，
you can think of self driving cars and robot manipulation,
你可以想到自动驾驶汽车和机器人操作，
but also very recently we've started seeing incredible advances of deep reinforcement learning,
但最近我们也开始看到深度强化学习令人难以置信的进步，
specifically also on the side of game play and strategy making as well.
特别是在游戏和策略制定方面。
So one really cool thing is that,
所以一件很酷的事情是，
now you can even imagine right this,
现在你甚至可以想象这个，
this combination of robotics, together with gameplay right,
这种机器人技术的结合，加上现在的游戏性，
now, training robots to play against us in the real world,
现在训练机器人在现实世界中与我们对抗，
and I'll just play this very short video on StarCraft and DeepMind.
我播放这段很短的星际争霸和 DeepMind 的视频。
Perfect information and to display in real time,
完美的信息和实时显示，
it also requires long term planning
它还需要长期规划
and the ability to choose what action to take from millions and millions of possibilities,
以及从千千万万种可能性中选择采取什么行动的能力，
I'm hoping for a five zero not to lose any games,
我希望五比零，不会输掉任何一场比赛，
but I think the realistic goal would be four and one in my favor.
但我认为现实的目标应该是四比一对我有利。
I think he looks more confident
我认为他看起来更自信了，
and Taylor was quite nervous before.
Taylor 之前也很紧张。
The room was much more tense this time,
这一次，房间里的气氛要紧张得多，
really didn't know what to expect,
真的不知道会发生什么，
he's been playing StarCraft pretty much since he five.
他从五岁起就一直玩星际争霸。
I wasn't expecting AI to be that good,
我没想到人工智能会这么好，
everything that he did was proper,
他所做的每一件事都是恰当的，
it was calculated and it was done well,
都是经过计算的，都做得很好，
I thought I'm learning something.
我想我学到了一些东西。
I would consider myself a good player, right,
我认为自己是个好玩家，
but I lost every single one of my games.
但我输掉了每一场比赛。
[] had won.
[]赢了。
So let's take maybe a start and take a step back,
所以让我们先开始，退后一步，
first of all, and think about how reinforcement learning fits into
首先，想想强化学习是如何适用于
this whole paradigm of all of the different topics that you've been exposed to in this class so far,
你在这节课上所接触到的所有不同主题的整个范例，
so as a whole,
作为一个整体，
I think that we've really covered two different types of learning in this course to date, right,
我认为到目前为止，我们在这门课程中已经涵盖了两种不同类型的学习，
up until now, we've really started focusing in the beginning part of the lectures,
到目前为止，我们已经开始关注课程的开始部分，
firstly on what we call supervised learning,
首先是我们所说的监督学习，
supervised learning is in this domain,
监督学习就是在这个领域，
where we're given data in the form of
我们给出数据格式，
x's our inputs and our label's y,
x 作为输入和 y 作为标签，
and our goal here is to learn a function or a neural network,
我们的目标是学习一个函数或神经网络，
that can learn to predict y, given our inputs x.
它可以学习预测 y ，给出我们的输入 x 。
So, for example, if you consider this example of an apple,
因此，例如，如果你考虑这个苹果的例子，
observing a bunch of images of apples we want to detect,
观察一系列我们想要检测的苹果的图像，
you know, in the future if we see a new image of an apple,
在未来，如果我们看到一个新的苹果图像，
to detect that this is indeed an apple.
来检测这确实是一个苹果。
Now, the second class of learning approaches that we've discovered yesterday,
我们在昨天发现的第二种学习方法，
in yesterday's lecture was that of unsupervised learning,
在昨天的课程中，（发现的）是无监督学习，
and in these algorithms,
在这些算法中，
you have only access to the data,
你只能访问数据，
there's no notion of labels, right,
没有标签的概念，
this is what we learned about yesterday,
这就是我们昨天了解到的，
in these types of algorithms,
在这些类型的算法中，
you're not trying to predict a label,
你不是在试图预测一个标签，
but you're trying to uncover some of the underlying structure,
而是试图揭示一些潜在的结构，
what we were calling basically these latent variables,
我们所称的这些潜在变量，
these hidden features in your data,
这些隐藏在你的数据中的特征，
so for example, in this apple example, right,
例如，在这个苹果的例子中，
using unsupervised learning,
使用了无监督学习，
the analogous example would basically be to build a model,
类似的例子基本上是建立一个模型，
that could understand and cluster certain certain parts of these images together,
可以理解这些图像的特定部分并将其聚集在一起，
and maybe it doesn't have to understand that necessarily,
也许它不需要理解，
this is an image of an apple,
这是一个苹果的图像，
but it needs to understand that,
但它需要明白，
you know, this image of the red apple is similar,
红色苹果的图像是相似于，
it has the same latent features and same semantic meaning
它具有相同的潜在特征和相同的语义，
as this black and white outline sketch of the Apple.
与这个黑白的苹果轮廓比起来。
Now, in today's lecture,
现在，在今天的课程中，
we're going to talk about yet another type of learning algorithms, right,
我们将讨论另一种类型的学习算法，
in reinforcement learning,
在强化学习中，
we're going to be only given data in the form of what are called state action pairs, right,
我们将只给出所谓的状态作用对形式的数据，
now states are observations, right,
现在状态是观察，
this is what the agent, let's call it,
这是 agent ，让我们这样称呼它，
the neural network is going to observe,
神经网络将会观察到，
it's what it sees,
这就是它所看到的，
the actions are the behaviors that this agent takes in those particular states,
这些操作是代理在这些特定状态下采取的行为，
so the goal of reinforcement learning is
所以，强化学习的目标是，
to build an agent that can learn how to maximize what are called rewards,
建立一个能够学习如何最大化奖励的 agent ，
this is the third component that is specific to reinforcement learning
这是第三个特定于强化学习的组件，
and you want to maximize all of those rewards over many, many time steps in the future,
你希望在未来的许多时间步骤中最大化所有这些奖励，
so again, in this apple example,
所以，在这个苹果的例子中，
we might now see that the agent doesn't necessarily learn that,
我们现在可能会看到 agent 不一定学习，
okay, this is an apple or it looks like these other apples,
好的，这是一个苹果，或者它看起来像其他苹果，
now it has to learn to,
现在它必须学习，
let's say, eat the apple, take an action, eat that apple,
比如，吃苹果，采取行动，吃那个苹果，
because it has learned that,
因为它已经学习到，
eating that apple makes it live longer
吃苹果能让它活得更长，
or survive because it doesn't starve.
或者因为它不会挨饿而存活下来。
So in today, right, like I said,
所以今天，就像我说的，
we're going to be focusing exclusively on this third type of learning paradigm,
我们将专门关注第三种类型的学习范式，
which is reinforcement learning.
也就是强化学习。
And before we go any further,
在我们继续之前，
I just want to start by building up some very key terminology and like, basically background for all of you,
我只想先为大家建立一些非常关键的术语和背景知识，
so that we're all on the same page,
这样我们能够达成一致，
when we start discussing some of the more complex components of today's lecture.
当我们开始讨论今天课程中一些更复杂的部分时。
So, let's start by building up, you know, some of this terminology,
所以，让我们从建立一些这样的术语开始，
the first main piece of terminology is that of an agent,
第一个主要术语是 agent ，
an agent is a being basically that can take actions,
agent 是一种可以采取行动的存在，
for example, you can think of an agent as a machine, right,
例如，你可以将 agent 视为一台机器，
that is, let's say an autonomous drone that is making a delivery,
也就是，让我们假设一架正在送货的自动无人机，
or for example, in a game,
或者例如，在游戏中，
it could be Super Mario,
它可能是超级马里奥，
that's navigating inside of your video, video game,
在你的视频游戏中导航，
the algorithm itself,
算法本身，
it's important to remember that the algorithm is the agent, right,
重要的是要记住算法就是 agent ，
we're trying to build an agent that can do these tasks,
我们试图构建一个可以完成这些任务的 agent ，
and the algorithm is that agent,
算法就是这个 agent ，
so in life, for example,
所以在生活中，
all of you are agents in life.
你们所有人都是生活中的 agent 。
The environment is the other kind of contrary approach
环境对 agent 来说是另一种相反的方法，
or the contrary perspective to the agent,
或相反的观点，
the environment is simply the world where that agent lives and where it operates,
环境就是 agent 生活和运作的世界，
right, where it exists and it moves around in,
就在它存在的地方，它在里面活动，
the agent can send commands to that environment
agnet 可以将命令发送到环境，
in the form of what are called actions,
以所谓的操作的形式，
you can take actions in that environment
你可以在该环境中执行操作，
and let's call for notation purposes,
让我们称为表示法，
let's say the possible set of all actions that it could take is,
假设它可以采取的所有行动的可能集合是，
let's say a set of A, right,
假设是一组 A ，
now, it should be noted that,
现在，应该注意的是，
agents at any point in time could choose amongst this,
agent 可以在任何时间点进行选择，
let's say list of possible actions,
比如可能的操作列表，
but of course, in some situations,
当然，在某些情况下，
your action space does not necessarily need to be a finite space,
你的动作空间不一定需要是有限空间，
maybe you could take actions in a continuous space,
也许你可以在一个连续的空间里采取行动，
for example, when you're driving a car,
例如，当你驾驶一辆汽车时，
you're taking actions on a continuous angle space
你是在一个连续的角度空间上采取行动，
of what angle you want to steer that car,
该空间是你想要驾驶汽车的角度，
it's not necessarily just going right or left or straight,
它不一定只是向右、向左或直行，
you may steer at any continuous degree.
你可以在任何连续的角度上驾驶。
Observations is essentially how the environment responds back to the agent, right,
观察本质上是环境对 agent 的反应，
the environment can tell the agent,
环境可以告诉 agent ，
you know what it should be seeing based on those actions that it just took,
根据它刚刚采取的操作，它应该看到什么，
and it responds in the form of what is called a state,
并且它以所谓的状态的形式做出响应，
a state is simply a concrete and immediate situation,
状态是具体和直接的情况，
that the agent finds itself in at that particular moment.
agent 在那个特定时刻发现自己所处的。
Now it's important to remember that,
现在重要的是要记住，
unlike other types of learning that we've covered in this course,
不同于我们在本课程中讨论的其他类型的学习，
reinforcement learning is a bit unique,
强化学习是有点独特的，
because it has one more component here in addition to these other components,
因为它除了这些其他组件之外，还有一个组件，
which is called the reward,
它被称为奖励，
now, the reward is a feedback by which we measure,
奖励是我们衡量的反馈，
or we can try to measure the success of a particular agent in its environment.
或者我们可以尝试衡量某个 agent 在其环境中的成功。
So, for example, in a video game,
例如，在电子游戏中，
when Mario grabs a coin, for example,
当马里奥拿起一枚硬币时，
he wins points, right,
他就会赢得分数，
so from a given state,
所以，在给定的状态下，
an agent can send out any form of actions to take some decisions,
agent 可以发出任何形式的操作来做出某些决定，
and those actions may or may not result in rewards being collected and accumulated over time.
这些操作可能会也可能不会导致奖励随着时间的推移而收集和积累。
Now, it's also very important to remember that,
现在，同样重要的是要记住，
not all actions result in immediate rewards,
并不是所有的行动都会带来立竿见影的奖励，
you may take some actions that will result in a reward in a delayed fashion,
你可能会采取一些行动，以一种延迟的方式得到奖励，
maybe in a few time steps down the future,
也许在未来的几步时间里，
maybe in life, maybe years,
也许在生活中，在几年后，
you may take an action today, that results in a reward many some time from now,
你今天采取的行动可能会在很长一段时间后产生奖励，
and, but essentially all of these try to effectively evaluate some way
但基本上所有这些都试图有效地评估某种方式
of measuring the success of a particular action that an agent takes.
来衡量 agent 采取的特定行动的成功程度。
So, for example, when we look at the total rewards,
因此，例如，当我们查看总奖励，
that an agent accumulates over the course of its lifetime,
agent 在其生命周期中积累的总奖励时，
we can simply sum up all of the rewards,
我们可以简单地将所有奖励相加，
that an agent gets after a certain time t, right,
agetn 在特定时间 t 后获得的所有奖励，
so this Rt is the sum of all rewards from that point on into the future into infinity,
所以这个 Rt 是从那个点到未来无限远的所有奖励的总和，
and that can be expanded to look exactly like this,
它可以扩展成像这样的样子，
it's reward time t plus the reward time t+1 plus t+2,
rt 加上 rt+1 加上 rt+2 ，
and so on and so forth.
以此类推。
Often it's actually very useful for all of us
通常，对我们所有人来说，
to consider not only the sum of all of these rewards,
不仅考虑所有这些奖励的总和，
but instead what's called the discounted sum.
而且考虑所谓的折扣总和，
So you can see here,
所以你可以看到，
I've added this γ factor in front of all of the rewards,
我在所有奖励的前面添加了这个 γ 因子，
and that discounting factor is essentially multiplied by every future reward
折扣因子是乘以每个未来的奖励，
that the agent sees and it's discovered by the agent,
agent 看到，并被 agent 发现的，
and the reason that we want to do this is
我们想要这么做的原因是，
actually this dampening factor is designed
这个抑制因素的设计，
to make future rewards essentially worth less than rewards that we might see at this instant,
是使未来的奖励比我们现在可能看到的奖励更有价值，
at this moment right now.
在这个时刻。
Now, you can think of this as basically enforcing some kind of short term greiness in the algorithm, right,
现在，你可以认为这是在执行某种短期算法中的灰色，
so for example, if I offered you a reward of five dollars today
例如，如果我今天给你们 5 美元的奖励，
or a reward of five dollars and ten years from now,
或者 10 年后给你们 5 美元的奖励，
I think all of you would prefer that five dollars today,
我想你们所有人都会更喜欢今天的 5 美元，
simply because we have that same discounting factor applied to this, to this processing,
因为我们在这个过程种有同样的折扣因素，
we have that factor,
我们有一个因素，
that that five dollars is not worth as much to us,
那 5 美元对我们来说不值那么多钱，
if it's given to us ten years in the future,
如果十年后给我们的话，
and that's exactly how this is captured here as well,
这也正是我们在这里捕捉到的，
mathematically, this discounting factor is like multiply,
从数学上讲，这个折扣因子就像乘以，
like I said, multiply that every single future award exponentially,
就像我说的，乘以每一个未来的奖项，将呈指数级增长，
and it's important to understand that also,
理解这一点也很重要，
typically this discounting factor is, you know, between 0 and 1,
通常情况下，折扣系数介于 0 和 1 之间，
there are some exceptional cases where maybe you want some strange behaviors
在某些特殊情况下，你可能想要一些奇怪的行为，
and have a discounting factor greater than 1,
折现系数大于 1 ，
but in general, that's not something we're going to be talking about today.
但总的来说，这不是我们今天要讨论的问题。
Now finally, it's very important in reinforcement learning,
最后，这在强化学习中非常重要，
this special function called the Q-function,
这个特殊的函数被称为 Q 函数，
which ties in a lot of these different components that I've just shared with you altogether.
它与我刚才与你们分享的许多不同的组件联系在一起。
Now, let's look at what this Q-function is, right.
现在让我们来看看这个 Q 函数是什么。
So we already covered this Rt function, right,
所以我们已经讨论了这个 Rt 函数，
Rt is the discounted sum of rewards
Rt 是奖励折扣和，
from time t all the way into the future time infinity,
从时间 t 一直到未来无限时间，
but remember that this Rt, right,
但请记住，这个 Rt ，
it's discounted number one and number two,
它是折扣 1 和 2 ，
we're going to try and build a Q-function,
我们将尝试构建 Q 函数，
that captures the the maximum or the best action that we could take,
它捕捉我们可以采取的最大或最好的行动，
that will maximize this reward.
以最大化这一奖励。
So let me say that one more time in a different way,
所以让我用一种不同的方式再说一次，
the Q-function takes as input, two different things,
Q 函数接受两个不同的东西作为输入，
the first is the state that you're currently in
第一个是你当前所处的状态，
and the second is a possible action that you could execute in this particular state,
第二个是你可以在特定状态下执行的可能操作，
so here's st is that state at time t,
所以这里 st 是时间 t 的状态，
at is that action that you may want to take at time t,
at 是你可能想要在时间 t 采取的行动，
and the Q-function of these two pieces is going to denote or capture,
Q 函数的这两个部分将表示或捕捉，
what the expected total return would be of that agent,
那个 agent 预期总奖励是多少，
if it took that action in that particular state.
如果 agent 在特定状态下采取该行动。
Now, one thing that I think maybe we should all be asking ourselves now is
现在，我认为我们现在都应该问问自己，
this seems like a really powerful function, right,
这似乎是一个非常强大的函数，
if you had access to this type of a function, this Q-function,
如果你可以访问这种类型的函数，这个 Q 函数，
I think you could actually perform a lot of tasks right off the that, right,
我想你可以立即执行很多任务，
so if you wanted to, for example, understand how to what actions to take in a particular state,
例如，如果你想了解如何在特定的状态下采取什么动作，
and let's suppose I gave you this magical Q-function,
让我们假设我给了你这个神奇的 Q 函数，
does anyone have any ideas of
有人有什么想法，
how you could transform that Q-function to directly infer what action should be taken?
你如何转换这个 Q 函数来直接推断应该采取什么动作吗？
Given a state,
给定一个状态，
you can look at your possible action space
你可以查看可能的操作空间，
and pick the one that gives you the highest Q value.
并选择给你最高 Q 值的操作空间。
Exactly, so that's exactly right.
完全正确，所以这是完全正确的。
So just to repeat that one more time,
所以再重复一次，
the Q-function tells us for any possible action, right,
Q 函数告诉我们任何可能的操作，
what is the expected reward for that action to be taken,
采取这一行动的预期奖励是什么，
so if we wanted to take a specific action given in a specific state,
所以，如果我们想要在特定的状态采取特定的行动，
ultimately we need to,
最终我们需要，
you know, figure out which action is the best action,
找出哪种行动是最好的行动，
the way we do that from a Q-function is
我们通过 Q 函数做到这一点的方法是，
simply to pick the action that will maximize our future reward,
简单地选择将使我们未来的奖励最大化的行动，
and we can simply try out number one,
我们可以简单地尝试第一个，
if we have a discrete action space,
如果我们有一个离散的动作空间，
we can simply try out all possible actions,
我们可以简单地尝试所有可能的动作，
compute their Q value for every single possible actions,
计算每个可能行动的 Q 值，
based on the state that we currently find ourselves in,
根据我们目前所处的状态，
and then we pick the action that is going to result in the highest Q value,
然后我们选择将产生最高 Q 值的动作，
if we have a continuous action space,
如果我们有一个连续的动作空间，
maybe we do something a bit more intelligent,
也许我们会做一些更智能的事情，
maybe following the gradients along this Q value curve
也许沿着这条 Q 值曲线的梯度，
and maximizing it as part of an optimization procedure.
并将其最大化作为优化过程的一部分。
But generally in this lecture,
但总的来说，在这节课中，
what I want to focus on is,
我想要关注的是，
actually how we can obtain this Q-function.
我们如何才能得到这个 Q 函数。
To start with, I I kind of skipped a lot of steps in that last slide,
首先，我跳过了上一张幻灯片中的很多步骤，
where I just said,
我刚才说，
let's suppose I give you this magical Q-function,
假设我给你一个神奇的 Q 函数，
how can you determine what action to take,
你如何确定要采取什么行动，
but in reality, we're not given that Q-function,
但在现实中，我们没有得到 Q 函数，
we have to learn that Q-function using deep learning,
我们必须使用深度学习来学习 Q 函数，
and that's what today's lecture is going to be talking about primarily is,
这就是今天的课程将主要讨论的，
first of all, how can we construct and learn that Q-function from data,
首先，我们如何从数据中构造和学习 Q 函数，
and then of course, the final step is use that Q-function to,
当然，最后一步是使用 Q 函数，
you know, take some actions in the real world.
在现实世界中采取一些行动。
And broadly speaking, there are two classes of reinforcement learning algorithms,
总的来说，有两类强化学习算法，
that we're going to briefly touch on as part of today's lecture.
我们将简要介绍一下，作为今天课程的一部分。
The first class is what's going to be called value learning,
第一类就是所谓的价值学习，
and that's exactly this process that we've just talked about,
这就是我们刚才谈到的这个过程，
value learning tries to estimate our Q-function, right,
价值学习试图估计我们的 Q 函数，
so to find that Q-function,
所以为了找到 Q 函数，
Q given our state and our action,
Q 给定状态和行为，
and then use that Q-function to,
然后使用 Q 函数来，
you know optimize for the best action to take given a particular state that we find ourselves in.
优化给定的特定状态下要采取的最佳行动。
The second class of algorithms,
第二类算法，
which we'll touch on right at the end of today's lecture,
我们将在今天课程的最后谈到，
is kind of a different framing of this same approach,
是这种方法的一种不同的框架，
but instead of first optimizing the Q-function and finding a Q value
但是，不是首先优化 Q 函数并找到 Q 值，
and then using that Q-function to optimize our actions,
然后使用 Q 函数来优化我们的操作，
what if we just try to directly optimize our policy,
如果我们只尝试直接优化我们的策略，
which is what action to take based on a particular state that we find ourselves in,
这是根据我们发现自己所处的特定状态采取的操作，
if we do that, if we can obtain this function, right,
如果我们这样做，如果我们能得到这个函数，
then we can directly sample from that policy distribution
然后，我们可以直接从该策略分布中进行抽样，
to obtain the optimal action.
以获得最优操作。
We'll talk more details about that later in the lecture,
我们将在后面的课程中详细讨论这一点，
but first let's cover this first class of approaches, which is Q learning approaches,
但首先让我们讨论第一类方法，即 Q 学习方法，
and we'll build up that intuition and that knowledge onto the second part of policy learning.
我们将在策略学习的第二部分建立直觉和知识。
So maybe let's start by just digging a bit deeper into the Q-function specifically,
所以让我们从更深入地研究 Q 函数开始，
just to start to understand, you know, how we could estimate this in the beginning.
开始理解，我们如何在一开始估计它。
So first let me introduce this game,
所以首先让我来介绍一下这个游戏，
maybe some of you recognize this,
也许你们中的一些人认识到这一点，
this is the game of called Atari Breakout,
这是一个叫做 Atari Breakout 的游戏，
the the game here is essentially one where the agent is able to move left or right,
这里的游戏本质上是一个 agent 能够向左或向右移动，
this paddle on the bottom left or right,
这个桨在左下角或右下角，
and the objective is to move it in a way that this ball that's coming down towards the bottom of the screen
我们的目标是以这样一种方式移动它，
can be, you know, bounced off of your paddle, reflected back up,
这个向屏幕底部落下的球可以从你的球拍上反弹，反射回来，
and essentially you want to break out, right,
基本上你想要突破，
reflect that ball back up to the top of the screen towards the rainbow portion
把那个球反射回屏幕顶部的彩虹部分，
and keep breaking off,
然后继续打破，
every time you hit a pixel on the top of the screen,
每当你点击屏幕顶部的一个像素，
you break off that pixel,
你就会打断那个像素，
and the objective of the game is to basically eliminate all of those rainbow pixels, right,
这个游戏的目标是基本上消除所有的彩虹像素，
so you want to keep hitting that ball against the top of the screen
所以你想要继续击打屏幕顶部的球，
until you remove all the pixels.
直到你移除所有的像素。
Now the Q-function tells us,
现在 Q 函数告诉我们，
you know, the expected total return or the total reward that we can expect
我们预期的总回报或总奖励，
based on a given state and action pair,
基于给定的状态和行动，
that we may find ourselves in this game.
我们可能会在这场游戏中自己发现。
Now, the first point I want to make here is that,
现在，我想在这里提出的第一点是，
sometimes even for us as humans to understand what the q value should be
有时候，即使是我们人类，理解 Q 值应该是什么，
is sometimes quite unintuitive, right.
有时也是相当不直观的。
So here's one example,
这里有一个例子，
let's say we find these two state action pairs right here is A and B,
假设我们发现这两个状态动作对是 A 和 B ，
two different options, that we can be presented with in this game,
两个不同的选项，我们可以在这个游戏中看到，
A, the ball is coming straight down towards us,
A ，球径直朝我们飞过来，
that's our state,
那是我们的状态，
our action is to do nothing
我们的行动是什么都不做，
and simply reflect that ball back up vertically up,
只是把球垂直向上反射回来，
the second situation,
第二种情况，
the state is basically that the ball is coming slightly at an angle,
球的状态是以一个角度微微地飞过来，
we're not quite underneath it yet
我们还没有完全处于它的下面，
and we need to move towards it
我们需要朝着它前进，
and actually hit that ball in a way that you know will will make it and not miss it hopefully, right,
并以一种你知道会成功而不是错失的方式来击球，
So hopefully that ball doesn't pass below us
所以希望那个球不会传到我们下面，
and the game would be over,
比赛就结束了，
can you imagine,
你能想象一下，
you know which of these two options might have a higher Q value for the network,
这两个选项中哪一个可能对网络具有更高的 Q 值，
which one would result in a rate of reward for the neural network or for the agent,
哪一个会导致对神经网络或 agent 的回报率，
so how many people believe A would result in a higher return,
那么，有多少人相信 A 会带来更高的回报，
how about B,
B 怎么样，
okay, how about someone who picked B,
好的，那选 B 的人，
can you tell me why B?
你能告诉我为什么选 B 吗？
[], you're actually doing something.
[]，你真的在做一些事情。
Okay, yeah, about more?
好的，是的，还有更多吗？
For the, for A, you only have like the maximum you can take off is like one,
对于 A ，你可以拿到的最大值就一，
because after you reflect,
因为当你反射后，
your automatically [background] more than.
你自动[背景]更多。
Exactly and actually there's a very interesting thing,
正确，这里有一个非常有趣的事情，
so when I first saw this,
所以当我第一次看到这个的时候，
actually it's, it was very unintuitive for me,
它是，这对我来说是非常不直观的，
why A is actually working much worse than B,
为什么 A 比 B 差得多，
but in general, with this very conservative action of B,
但总的来说， B 的这个非常保守的动作，
your kind of exactly like you said,
就像你说的，
the two answers were implying,
两个答案都在暗示，
is that A is a very conservative action,
A 是一个非常保守的动作，
you're kind of only going up and down,
你只是上上下下而已，
it will achieve a good reward,
它将获得很好的回报，
it will solve the game, right,
它会解决这个游戏，
in fact, it solves the game exactly like this right here,
事实上，它像这样解决了这个游戏，
you can see,
你可以看到，
in general, this action is going to be quite conservative,
总的来说，这一行动将是相当保守的，
it's just bouncing up,
它只是反弹起来，
hitting one point at a time from the top
从顶端一次击中一分，
and breaking off very slowly,
然后非常缓慢地脱离，
the board that you can see here,
你可以在这里看到的板，
but in general, you see the part of the board that's being broken off
但总的来说，你可以看到板被拆分的部分
is towards the center of the board, right,
是朝向板的中心的，
not much on edges of the board,
不是很多在板的边缘，
if you look at B,
如果你查看 B ，
now with b, you're kind of having agency,
现在，使用 B ，你就有了某种作用力，
like one of the answers said,
就像其中一个答案所说的，
you're coming towards the ball
你朝着球走来，
and what that implies is that
这意味着，
you're sometimes going to actually hit the corner of your paddle
你有时会撞到你的球拍的角落，
and have a very extreme angle on your paddle
在你的球拍上有一个非常极端的角度，
and hit the sides of the board as well,
也击中了板的两边，
and it turns out that the algorithm, the agent can actually learn,
事实证明，算法， agent 可以了解到，
that hitting the sides of the board can have some kind of unexpected consequences,
击中板的两边可能会产生某种意想不到的后果，
that look like this,
就像这样，
so here you see it trying to enact that policy,
所以在这里，你可以看到它试图制定这项策略，
it's targeting the sides of the board,
它的目标是板的侧面，
but once it reaches a breakout on the side of the board,
但一旦它到达板一侧的突破口，
it found this hack in the solution,
它就在解决方案中发现了这个攻击，
where now it's breaking off a ton of points,
现在它正在打破大量的像素，
so that was kind of a trick that this neural network learned,
所以这是这个神经网络学到的一种技巧，
it was a way that it even moves away from the ball as it's coming down just,
这是一种在球落下的时候它甚至离开球的方式，
so we could move back towards it,
这样我们就可以向它移动，
just to hit it on the corner
只是在角上击球，
and execute on those those corner parts of the board
在板的角部执行，
and break out a lot of pieces for free almost.
几乎是免费的打破了很多部分。
So now that we can see that,
现在我们可以看到，
sometimes obtaining the Q-function can be a little bit unintuitive,
有时获得 Q 函数可能有点不直观，
but the key point here is that,
但这里的关键点是，
if we have the Q-function,
如果我们有 Q 函数，
we can directly use it to determine,
我们可以直接使用它来确定，
you know, what is the best action
我们可以采取的最佳行动是什么，
that we can take in any given state that we find ourselves in.
在我们发现自己处于任何给定的状态下。
So now the question naturally is,
所以，现在的问题自然是，
how can we train a neural network,
我们如何才能训练出一个神经网络，
that can indeed learn this Q-function?
真正能够学习这个 Q 函数？
So the type of the neural network here,
所以神经网络的类型，
naturally, because we have a function that takes as input two things,
很自然地，因为我们有一个函数，它接受两个东西作为输入，
let's imagine our neural network will also take as input these two objects as well,
让我们想象一下，我们的神经网络也将这两个对象作为输入，
one object is going to be the state of the board,
一个目标将是板的状态，
you can think of this as simply the pixels that are on the screen describing that board,
你可以简单地将其视为屏幕上描述该板的像素，
so it's an image of the board at a particular time,
所以这是板在特定时间的图像，
maybe you want to even provide two or three images
也许你甚至想提供两三张图片，
to give it some sense of temporal information and some past history as well,
给它一些时间信息和一些过去的历史的感觉，
but all of that information can be combined together
但所有这些信息都可以组合在一起，
and provided to the network in the form of a state.
并以状态的形式提供给网络。
And in addition to that, you may also want to provide some actions as well, right,
除此之外，你可能还想提供一些操作，
so in this case,
所以，在这种情况下，
the actions that a neural network or an agent could take in this game is
神经网络或 agent 在这个游戏中可以采取的行动是
to move to the right, to the left, to stay still,
向右移动，向左移动，保持不动，
and those could be three different actions,
这可能是三个不同的动作，
that could be provided and parameterized to the input of a neural network,
可以提供给神经网络的输入并将其参数化，
the goal here is to, you know, estimate the single number output,
这里的目标是估计单个数字的产出，
that measures what is the expected value or the expected Q value
它测量期望值或期望 Q 值是多少，
of this neural network at this particular state action pair,
关于这个神经网络在这个特定状态作用对的，
now oftentimes what you'll see is that,
通常你会看到，
if you wanted to evaluate,
如果你想评估，
let's suppose a very large action space,
假设有一个非常大的动作空间，
it's going to be very inefficient to try the approach on the left,
尝试左边的方法，效率会非常低，
with, with a very large action space,
在一个很大的行动空间中，
because what it would mean is that you'd have to run your neural network forward many different times
因为这意味着你将不得不多次向前运行你的神经网络，
one time for every single element of your action space,
对于你动作空间的每一个元素一次，
so what if instead you only provided it an input of your state
所以，如果你只给它提供了你所在状态的一个输入，
and as output you gave it, let's say all n different Q values,
作为你给它的输出，假设所有 n 个不同的 Q 值，
one Q value for every single possible action,
每一个可能的动作都有一个 Q 值，
that way you only need to run your neural network once for the given state that you're in,
这样，你只需要针对你所处的特定状态运行一次神经网络，
and then that neural network will tell you for all possible actions, what's the maximum,
然后神经网络会告诉你所有可能的动作，最大值是多少，
you simply then look at that output
然后，你只需查看该输出，
and pick the action that has the [] Q value.
并选择具有 [] Q 值的动作。
Now, what would happen, right,
现在，会发生什么，
So actually the question I want to pose here is really,
所以我想在这里提出的问题是，
you know, we want to train one of these two networks,
我们想要训练这两个网络中的一个，
let's stick with the network on the right for simplicity,
为了简单起见，让我们继续使用右侧的网络，
just since it's a much more efficient version of the network on the left,
因为它是左侧网络的一个更高效的版本，
and the question is,
问题是，
you know, how do we actually train that network on the right,
我们如何真正在右边训练这个网络，
and specifically I want all of you to think about really the best case scenario
具体地说，我希望你们所有人都考虑最好的情况，
just to start with how an agent would perform ideally in a particular situation
首先考虑一个 agent 在特定情况下会如何理想地表现，
or what would happen if an agent took all of the ideal actions at any given state,
或者如果一个 agent 在任何给定的状态下采取所有理想的行动会发生什么，
this would mean that essentially the target return, right,
这将意味着，从本质上讲，目标回报，
the, the predicted or the the value that we're trying to predict the target
无论是我们试图预测的值，还是预测的值目标，
is going to always be maximized, right,
总是最大化的，
and this can serve as essentially the ground truth to the agent.
这可以作为 agent 的基本事实。
Now, for example, to do this,
现在，例如，要做到这一点，
we want to formulate a loss function,
我们想要建立一个损失函数，
that's going to essentially represent our expected return,
它代表了我们的预期回报，
if we're able to take all of the best actions, right,
如果我们能够采取所有最好的行动，
so, for example, if we select an initial reward
所以，举个例子，如果我们选择一个最初的奖励，
plus selecting some action in our action space,
加上在我们的行动空间中选择一些行动，
that maximizes our expected return,
以最大化我们的预期回报，
then for the next future state,
那么对于下一个未来状态，
we need to apply that discounting factor and recursively apply the same equation,
我们需要应用这个贴现因子，并递归地应用相同的等式，
and that simply turns into our target.
这就变成了我们的目标。
Right, now we can ask basically what does our neural network predict, right,
现在，我们可以问，我们的神经网络预测了什么，
so that's our target,
这就是我们的目标，
and we recall from previous lectures,
我们从以前的课程中回忆，
if we have a target value,
如果我们有一个目标值，
in this case, our Q value is a continuous variable,
在这种情况下，我们的 Q 值是一个连续变量，
we have also a predicted variable,
我们还有一个预测变量，
that is going to come as part of the output of every single one of these potential actions that could be taken,
它将作为可能采取的每一项潜在行动的输出的一部分，
we can define what's called a Q-loss,
我们可以定义所谓的 Q 损失，
which is essentially just a very simple mean squared error loss between these two continuous variables,
它本质上就是这两个连续变量之间非常简单的均方误差损失，
we minimize their distance over two over many, many different iterations
我们将它们之间的距离最小化，
of [] our neural network in this environment,
在这个环境中[]我们的神经网络，
observing actions and observing not only the actions,
观察动作，不仅观察动作，
but most importantly after the action is,
最重要的是在动作之后，
committed or executed,
无论是提交还是执行，
we can see exactly the ground truth, expected return, right,
我们都能看到实情，预期回报，
so we have the ground truth labels to train and supervise this model
我们有事实标签来直接训练和监督这个模型，
directly from the actions that were executed as part of random selection, for example.
作为随机选择的一部分执行的操作。
Now, let me just stop right there
现在，让我到此为止，
and maybe summarize the whole process one more time
也许再总结一次整个过程，
and maybe a bit different terminology,
也许会有一些不同的术语，
just to give everyone kind of a different perspective on this same problem.
只是为了让每个人对这个相同的问题有不同的看法。
So our deep neural network that we're trying to train looks like this, right,
所以我们试图训练的深度神经网络是这样的，
it takes as input state
它接受 state 作为输入，
is trying to output n different numbers,
尝试输出 n 个不同的数字，
those n different numbers correspond to the Q value associated to n different actions,
这 n 个不同的数字对应于与 n 个不同动作相关联的 Q 值，
one Q value per action,
每个动作一个 Q 值，
here the actions in Atari breakout, for example, should be three actions,
例如 Atari Breakout 中的行动应该是三个行动，
we can either go left, we can go right,
我们要么向左走，要么向右走，
or we can do nothing, we can stay where we are, right.
或者什么都不做，我们可以呆在原地不动，
So, the next step from this we saw,
所以，下一步，我们看到，
if we have this Q value output,
如果我们有这个 Q 值输出，
what we can do with it is,
我们可以做的是，
we can make an action or we can even let me be more formal about it,
我们用它做一个动作，或者我们甚至可以让我更正式地对待它，
we can develop what's called a policy function,
我们可以开发所谓的策略函数，
policy function is a function that given a state,
策略函数是一个给定状态的函数，
it determines what is the best action,
它决定什么是最好的行动，
so that's different than the Q-function, right,
这和 Q 函数是不同的，
the Q-function tells us
Q 函数告诉我们，
given a state, what is the best or what is the value, the return of every action that we could take,
给定一个状态，什么是最好的，或者是什么值，以及我们可以采取的每个行动的回报，
the policy function tells us one step more than that,
策略函数告诉我们更进一步，
given, given a state, what is the best action, right,
给定一个状态，最好的行动是什么，
so it's a very end to end way of thinking about,
所以这是一种非常端到端的思考方式，
you know, the agent's decision making process based on what I see right now,
根据我现在看到的 agent 的决策过程，
what is the action that I should take,
我应该采取什么行动，
and we can determine that policy function directly from the Q-function itself
我们可以直接从 Q 函数本身确定策略函数，
simply by maximizing and optimizing all of the different Q values
只需最大化和优化所有不同的 Q 值，
for all of the different actions that we see here.
对于我们在这里看到的所有不同的操作。
So for example, here we can see that,
例如，我们在这里可以看到，
given this state, the Q-function,
在给定这种状态下， Q 函数，
as the result of these three different values
作为这三个不同值的结果，
has A Q value of 20, if it goes to the left,
有一个 Q 值为 20 ，如果它向左移动，
has a Q value of 3, if it stays in the same place
有一个 Q 值为 3 ，如果它停留在同一位置，
and it has a Q value of 0,
它的 Q 值为 0 ，如果它向右移动，
it's going to basically die after this iteration,
它基本上会在迭代后消亡，
if it moves to the right,
如果它向右移动，
because you can see that the ball is coming to the left of it,
因为你可以看到球正在向它的左侧移动，
if it moves to the right, the game is over, right,
如果它向右移动，游戏就结束了，
so it needs to move to the left, in order to do that, in order to continue the game,
所以它需要向左移动才能继续比赛，
and the Q value reflects that,
Q 值反映了这一点，
the optimal action here is simply going to be the maximum of these three Q values,
这里的最优行动就是这三个 Q 值中的最大值，
in this case, it's going to be 20,
在这种情况下，它将是 20 ，
and then the action is going to be the corresponding action that comes from that 20,
然后动作将是来自 20 的相应动作，
which is moving left.
也就是向左移动。
Now, we can send this action back to the environment,
现在，我们可以将这个动作发送回环境，
in the form of the game, to execute the next step, right,
以游戏的形式，以执行下一步，
and as the agent moves through this environment,
当 agent 在这个环境中移动时，
it's going to be responded with not only by new pixels that come from the game,
它不仅会得到来自游戏的新像素的响应，
but more importantly, some reward signal,
更重要的是，一些奖励信号，
now, it's very important to remember that,
现在非常重要的是要记住，
the reward signals in pong, or sorry in Atari Breakout are very sparse, right,
在乒乓球中或在 Atari Breakout 中的奖励信号是非常稀疏的，
you get a reward, not necessarily based on the action that you take at this exact moment,
你会得到奖励，不一定是基于你在这一时刻所采取的行动，
it usually takes a few time steps for that ball to travel back up to the top of the screen,
球通常需要几个时间步骤才能回到屏幕顶部，
so usually your rewards will be quite delayed,
所以，通常情况下，你的奖励会非常延迟，
maybe at least by several time steps,
可能至少会延迟几个时间步长，
sometimes even more if you're bouncing off of the corners of the screen.
如果你在屏幕的角落里弹跳，有时甚至会延迟更多。
Now, one very popular or very famous approach that showed this
一种非常流行或非常著名的方法来展示这一点，
was presented by DeepMind, Google DeepMind several years ago,
是由 Google Deepmind 在几年前提出的，
where they showed that you could train a Q value network
他们展示了你可以训练 Q 值网络，
and you can see the input on the left hand side
你可以看到左侧的输入，
is simply the raw pixels coming from the screen,
只是来自屏幕的原始像素，
all the way to the actions of a controller on the right hand side,
一直到右侧控制器的动作，
and you could train this one network for a variety of different tasks
你可以训练这个网络来完成各种不同的任务，
all across the Atari Breakout ecosystem of games.
对于整个 Atari Breakout 游戏生态系统。
And for each of these tasks,
对于这些任务中的每一个，
the really fascinating thing that they showed was
他们展示的真正令人着迷的是，
for this very simple algorithm,
对于这个非常简单的算法，
which really relies on random choice of selection of actions
它真的依赖于随机选择动作，
and then, you know, learning from, you know, actions that don't do very well,
然后，从做得不是很好的动作中学习，
that you discourage them and trying to do actions that did perform well more frequently,
你阻止他们，尝试做那些执行得更好的动作，
very simple algorithm,
非常简单的算法，
but what they found was even with that type of algorithm,
但他们发现即使这种类型的算法，
they were able to surpass human level performance on over half of the game,
他们在比赛的一半以上时间里都超过了人类的水平，
there were some games that you can see here were still below human level performance,
你可以在这里看到一些游戏的表现仍然低于人类的水平，
but as we'll see,
但正如我们将看到的，
this was really like such an exciting advance,
这真的是一个如此令人兴奋的进步，
because of the simplicity of the algorithm
因为算法很简单，
and how you clean the formulation of the training was,
你是如何清理训练的公式的，
you only needed a very little amount of prior knowledge
你只需要将非常少量的先验知识，
to impose onto this neural network
强加给这个神经网络，
for it to be able to learn how to play these games,
它就能够学习如何玩这些游戏，
you never had to teach any of the rules of the game,
你从来没有教过任何游戏规则，
you only had to let it explore its environment,
你只需要让它探索它的环境，
play the game many, many times against itself,
与它自己玩这个游戏很多很多次，
and learn directly from that data.
然后直接从这些数据中学习。
Now there are several very important downsides of Q-learning
Q 学习有几个非常重要的缺点，
and hopefully these are going to motivate the second part of today's lecture,
希望这些能激励我们今天课程的第二部分，
which we'll talk about.
也就是我们要讨论的。
But the first one that I want to really convey to everyone here is that,
但我想在这里告诉大家的第一点是，
Q-learning is naturally applicable to discrete action spaces, right,
Q 学习自然适用于离散的动作空间，
because you can think of this output space that we're providing
因为你可以把我们提供的这个输出空间想象成
as kind of like one number per action that could be taken,
每一个可以执行的操作有一个数字，
now, if we have a continuous action space,
现在，如果我们有一个连续的行动空间，
we have to think about clever ways to work around that,
我们必须想出聪明的方法来解决这个问题，
in fact, there are now more recently there are some solutions
事实上，现在有了更多的解决方案，
to achieve Q-learning and continuous action spaces,
来实现 Q 学习和连续的动作空间，
but for the most part,
但在很大程度上，
Q-learning is very well suited for discrete action spaces,
Q 学习非常适合离散动作空间，
and we'll talk about ways of overcoming that with other approaches a bit later.
稍后我们会讨论用其他方法克服这个问题的方法。
And the second component here is that,
这里的第二个组成部分是，
the policy that we're learning, right,
我们正在学习的策略，
the Q-function is giving rise to that policy,
Q 函数产生了该策略，
which is the thing that we're actually using to determine what action to take,
这是我们用来确定要采取什么行动的东西，
given any state,
给出任何状态，
that policy is determined by, you know, deterministically optimizing that Q-funtion,
策略是通过优化 Q 函数来确定的，
we simply look at the results from the Q-function
我们只需查看 Q 函数的结果，
and apply our,
然后应用我们的，
or we, we look at the results of the Q-function
或者我们查看 Q 函数的结果，
and we pick the action that has the best or the highest Q value,
然后选择 Q 值最好或最高的操作，
that is very dangerous in many cases,
这在许多情况下是非常危险的，
because of the fact that it's always going to pick the best value for a given state,
因为它总是为给定的状态挑选最佳的值，
there's no stochasticity in that pipeline,
在管道中没有随机性，
so you can very frequently get caught in situations,
所以你经常会遇到这样的情况，
where you keep repeating the same actions
你一直在重复相同的动作，
and you don't learn to explore potentially different options that you may be thinking of.
而你没有学会探索你可能正在考虑的潜在的不同选择。
So to address these very important challenges,
因此，为了应对这些非常重要的挑战，
that's hopefully going to motivate now the next part of today's lecture,
这有望推动今天课程的下一部分，
which is going to be focused on policy learning,
重点是策略学习，
which is a different class of reinforcement learning algorithms that are different than Q-learning algorithms.
这是一种不同于 Q 学习算法的强化学习算法。
And like I said, those are called policy gradient algorithms
就像我说的，这些算法被称为策略梯度算法，
and policy gradient algorithms, the main difference is that,
策略梯度算法，主要的不同之处在于，
instead of trying to infer the policy from the Q-function,
不是试图从 Q 函数中推断出策略，
we're just going to build a neural network,
我们只需要构建一个神经网络，
that will directly learn that policy function from the data,
直接从数据中学习策略函数，
so it kind of skips one step
所以它跳过了一步，
and we'll see how we can train those networks.
我们将看看如何训练这些网络。
So before we get there,
所以在我们到达那里之前，
let me just revisit one more time,
让我再回顾一次，
the Q-function illustration that we are looking at, right,
我们看到的 Q 函数，
Q-function, we are trying to build a neural network outputs these Q values,
Q 函数，我们试图构建一个神经网络输出这些 Q 值，
one value per action,
每个操作一个值，
and we determine the policy by looking over this state of Q values,
我们通过查看 Q 值的这种状态来确定策略，
picking the value that has the highest,
选择具有最高值的值，
and looking at its corresponding action,
看看它对应的动作，
now with policy networks,
现在通过策略网络，
the idea that we want to keep here is that,
我们想要保留的想法是，
instead of predicting the Q values themselves,
不是预测 Q 值本身，
let's directly try to optimize this policy function,
而是直接尝试优化这一策略函数，
here we're calling the policy function π(s), right,
这里我们叫策略函数 π(s) ，
so π is the policy, s is our state,
所以 π 是策略， s 是我们的状态，
so it's a function that takes as input only the state
所以它是一个只接受状态作为输入的函数，
and it's going to directly output the action,
它将直接输出动作，
so the outputs here give us the desired action,
所以这里的输出给了我们应该采取的行动，
that we should take in any given state that we find ourselves in,
我们在任何给定的状态下应该采取的，
that represents not only the best action that we should take,
这不仅代表了我们应该采取的最佳行动，
but let's denote this as basically the probability that selecting that action
但是让我们把这个选择行动的概率，
would result in a very desirable outcome,
将产生非常理想的结果，
for our network,
对于我们的网络，
so not necessarily the value of that that action,
所以不一定是该操作的值，
but rather the probability that selecting that action would be the highest value, right,
而是选择该操作将是最高值的概率，
so, you don't care exactly about,
所以，你并不关心，
what is the numerical value that selecting this action takes or gives rise to rather,
选择此操作所采取或产生的确切数值是多少，
but rather, what is the likelihood,
而是，可能性是什么，
that selecting this action will give you the best performing value that you could expect,
选择此操作将为你提供预期的最佳值是多少，
exact value itself doesn't matter,
确切的值本身并不重要，
you only care about if selecting this action is going to give you, with high likelihood, the best one.
你只关心选择此操作是否会给您带来最好的结果。
So we can see that if these predicted probabilities here, right,
所以我们可以看到，如果这些预测的概率在这里，
in this example of Atari,
在这个 Atari 的例子中，
going left has the probability of being the highest value action with 90%,
向左移动的概率是最高值动作， 90% ，
staying in the center has a probability of 10%,
留在中间的概率为 10% ，
going right is 0%,
向右移动为 0% ，
so ideally, what our neural networks should do in this case is
在理想情况下，我们的神经网络应该做的是，
90% of the time in this situation go to the left,
在这种情况下， 90% 的时间向左，
10% of the time, it could still try staying at where it is,
10% 的时间，它仍然可以保持在原来的位置，
but never it should go to the right,
但永远不应该向右，
now note that this now is a probability distribution,
现在注意，这是一个概率分布，
this is very different than a Q-function,
这与 Q 函数有很大的不同，
a Q-function has actually no structure, right,
Q 函数实际上没有结构，
the Q values themselves can take any real number, right,
Q 值本身可以取任何实数，
but here the policy network has a very formulated output,
但在这里，策略网络有非常严格的输出，
all of the numbers here in the output have to sum to 1,
输出中的所有数字都必须求和为 1 ，
because this is a probability distribution, right,
因为这是一个概率分布，
and that gives it a very rigorous version of
这给了它一个非常严格的版本，
how we can train this model,
我们如何训练这个模型，
that makes it a bit easier to train than Q-function as well.
使它比 Q 函数更容易训练。
One other very important advantage of having an output that is a probability distribution is
输出是概率分布的另一个非常重要的优点是，
actually going to tie back to this other issue of Q-functions and Q neural networks that we saw before
将与我们之前看到的 Q 函数和 Q 神经网络的另一个问题联系在一起，
and that is the fact that q functions are naturally suited towards discrete action spaces,
这是 Q 函数自然适合离散动作空间的事实，
now when we're looking at this policy network,
现在，当我们看这个策略网络时，
we're puttingting a distributions, right,
我们考虑的是分布，
and remember those those distributions can also take continuous forms,
这些分布也可以采取连续的形式，
in fact, we've seen this in the last two lectures,
事实上，我们在上两节课中已经看到了这一点，
in the generative lecture,
在生成性课程中，
we saw how VAEs could be used to predict gaussian distributions over their latent space,
我们了解了如何使用 VAE 来预测其潜在空间上的高斯分布，
in the last lecture, we also saw how we could learn to predict uncertainties,
在上一节课中，我们还学习了如何预测不确定性，
which are continuous probability distributions using data,
这些使用数据的不确定性是连续的概率分布，
and just like that,
就像这样，
we could also use this same formulation
我们也可以使用同样的公式，
to move beyond discrete action spaces,
来超越离散的行动空间，
like you can see here,
就像你在这里看到的，
which are one possible action,
这是一个可能的行动，
a probability associated to one possible action,
一个与一个可能的行动相关的概率，
in a discrete set of possible actions,
在一组离散的可能动作中，
now we may have a space,
现在我们可能有一个空间，
which is not what action should I take,
不是我应该采取什么动作，
go left, right or say center,
向左，向右，或者说是居中，
but rather how quickly should I move
而是我应该移动的速度有多快，
and in what direction should I move, right,
我应该移动的方向，
that is a continuous variable as opposed to a discrete variable,
这是一个连续变量，而不是离散变量，
and you could say that now the answer should look like this,
你可以说现在的答案应该是这样的，
moving very fast to the right versus very slow to the,
向右移动的速度非常快或非常慢，
excuse me, very fast to the left versus very slow to the left,
抱歉，向左移动的速度非常快或非常慢，
has this continuous spectrum that we may want to model.
这是我们可能想要建模的连续谱。
Now, when we plot this entire distribution
现在，当我们画出整个分布，
of taking an action, giving a state,
采取行动，给出状态，
you can see basically a very simple illustration of that right here,
你可以在这里看到一个非常简单的图解，
this, this distribution has most of its mass over,
这个分布的大部分质量都超过了，
sorry, it has all of its mass over the entire real number line,
抱歉，它的所有质量都在整个实数线上，
first of all, it has most of its mass right in the optimal action space that we want to take,
首先，它在我们想要采取的最优行动空间中拥有大部分的质量，
so if we want to determine the best action to take,
所以，如果我们想要确定采取的最佳行动，
we would simply take the mode of this distribution,
我们将简单地采用这种分布模式，
the highest point, that would be the speed at which we should move and the direction that we should move in,
最高点，这将是我们应该前进的速度和我们应该前进的方向，
if we wanted to also, you know, try out different things and explore our space,
如果我们也想尝试不同的东西，探索我们的空间，
we could sample from this distribution and still obtain some stochasticity.
我们可以从这个分布中取样，仍然获得一些随机性。
Now, let's look at an example
现在让我们来看一个例子，
of how we can actually model these continuous distributions
我们如何对这些连续分布进行建模，
and actually we've already seen some examples of this in the previous two lectures like I mentioned,
我们已经在前面两节课中看到了一些例子，就像我提到的，
but let's take a look specifically in the context of reinforcement learning and policy gradient learning.
但让我们具体看看强化学习和策略梯度学习的背景。
So instead of predicting this probability of taking an action,
所以不是预测采取行动的概率，
giving all possible states,
给出所有可能的状态，
which in this case, there is now an infinite number of,
在这种情况下，现在有无限多的状态，
because we're in the continuous domain,
因为我们处于连续的域中，
we can't simply predict a single probability for every possible action,
我们不能简单地预测每个可能的行动的单一概率，
because there's an infinite number of them,
因为它们的数量是无限的，
so instead, what if we parameterized our action space by distribution, right,
因此，如果我们通过分布来参数化我们的动作空间，
so let's take for example, the gaussian distribution,
因此，让我们以高斯分布为例，
to parameterize a gaussian distribution,
将高斯分布参数化，
we only need two outputs, right,
我们只需要两个输出，
we need a mean and a variance,
我们需要一个均值和一个方差，
given a mean and a variance,
给定均值和方差，
we can actually have a probability mass
我们可以有一个概率质量，
and we can compute a probability over any possible action,
我们可以计算任何可能的行动的概率，
that we may want to take just from those two numbers,
我们可能想要从这两个数字，
so for example, in this image here,
例如，在这里的图像中，
we may want to output a gaussian that looks like this, right,
我们可能想要输出一个像这样的高斯分布，
its mean is centered at, let's see, -0.8,
它的平均值以 -0.8 为中心，
indicating that we should move basically left with a speed of 0.8 meters per second for example,
表示我们应该以每秒 0.8 米的速度向左移动，
and again we can see that,
我们再一次看到，
because this is a probability distribution,
因为这是一个概率分布，
because of the format of policy networks, right,
因为策略网络的格式，
we're enforcing that this is a probability distribution,
我们强制要求这是一个概率分布，
that means that the integral now of this, of this outputs right,
这意味着这个输出的积分，
by definition of it being a gaussian, must also integrate to 1.
按照它是高斯的定义，也必须积分为 1 。
Okay, great,
好的，太好了，
so now let's maybe take a look at how policy gradient networks can be trained
现在让我们来看看如何训练策略梯度网络，
and, you know, step through that process as well,
逐步完成这个过程，
as we look at a very concrete example,
我们来看看一个非常具体的例子，
and maybe let's start by just revisiting this reinforcement learning loop,
让我们从回顾强化学习循环开始，
that we started this class with.
这节课就是从这里开始的。
Now, let's specifically consider the example of training an autonomous vehicles,
现在，让我们具体考虑训练自动驾驶车辆的例子，
since I think that this is a particularly very intuitive example,
因为我认为这是一个特别非常直观的例子，
that we can walk through,
我们可以讨论的，
the agent here is the vehicle, right,
这里的 agent 是车，
the state could be obtained through many sensors,
状态可以通过很多传感器来获得，
that could be mounted on the vehicle itself,
安装在车辆身上，
so, for example, autonomous vehicles are typically equipped with sensors like cameras, lidars, radars etc,
例如，自动驾驶车辆通常配备摄像头、激光雷达、雷达等传感器，
all of these are giving observational inputs to the to the vehicle,
所有这些都为车辆提供观测输入，
the action that we could take is a steering wheel angle,
我们可以采取的行动是方向盘角度，
this is not a discrete variable, this is a continuous variable,
这不是一个离散变量。这是一个连续变量，
it's actually an angle that could take any real number,
这是一个可以取任何实数的角度，
and finally, the reward in this very simplistic example
最后奖励，在这个非常简单的例子中，
is the distance that we travel before we crash.
是我们在撞车前行驶的距离。
Okay, so now let's take a look at,
好的，现在让我们来看看，
how we could train a policy gradient neural network
如何训练一个策略梯度神经网络，
to solve this task of self driving cars
来解决这个自动驾驶汽车的任务，
as a concrete example.
作为一个具体的例子。
So we start by initializing our agent, right,
我们从初始化 agent 开始，
remember that we have no training data, right,
记住，我们没有训练数据，
so we have to think about actually reinforcement learning is almost like
所以我们不得不思考，强化学习就像是，
a data acquisition plus learning pipeline combined together,
数据获取和学习的管道结合在一起，
so the first part of that data acquisition pipeline is first
所以，数据采集管道的第一部分首先是，
to initialize our agent to go out and collect some data.
初始化我们的 agent ，以便收集一些数据。
So we start our vehicle, our agent,
所以我们开始我们的车，我们的 agent ，
and in the beginning, of course, it knows nothing about driving,
当然，在一开始，它对驾驶一无所知，
it's never been exposed to any of these rules of the environment or the observation before,
它以前从来没有接触过任何这些环境规则或观察，
so it runs its policy,
所以它运行它的策略，
which right now is untrained entirely,
现在完全没有训练，
until it terminates, right, until it goes outside of some bounds that we define,
直到它终止，直到它超出了我们定义的一些界限，
we measure basically the reward as the distance that it traveled before it terminated,
我们是用它在终止前行驶的距离来衡量奖励的，
and we record all of the states, all of the actions
我们记录了所有的状态，所有的行动，
and the final reward that it obtained until that termination, right,
和直到终止的最终的奖励，
this becomes our mini data set,
这将成为我们的迷你数据集，
that we'll use for the first round of training,
我们将在第一轮训练中使用它，
let's take those data sets,
让我们来看看这些数据集，
and now we'll do one step of training,
现在我们来做一个步骤的训练，
the first step of training that we'll do is
我们要做的训练的第一步是，
to take, to take the later half of our, of our trajectory that our agent ran
使用我们的 agent 运行的轨迹的后半部分，
and decreased the probability of actions that resulted in low rewards,
并减少导致低回报的行动的可能性，
now, because the vehicle we know the vehicle terminated,
现在，因为我们知道车终止了，
we can assume that,
我们可以假设，
all of the actions that occurred in the later half of this trajectory were probably not very good actions,
在这个轨迹的后半部分发生的所有动作都可能不是非常好的动作，
because they came very close to termination,
因为它们非常接近终止，
so let's decrease the probability of all of those things happening again in the future,
所以，让我们降低所有这些事情在未来再次发生的可能性，
and we'll take all of the things that happen in the beginning half of our training episode,
我们将考虑在我们的训练的前半部分发生的所有事情，
and we will increase their probabilities,
我们会增加他们的概率，
now, again, there's no reason,
现在，再说一次，我们没有理由，
why there shouldn't necessarily be a good action that we took in the first half of this trajectory
不在这个轨迹的前半部分采取好的行动，
and a bad action in the later half,
而在后半部分采取糟糕的行动，
but it's simply because actions that are in the later half were closer to a failure and closer determination,
但这只是因为后半部分的行动更接近失败，更接近终止，
that we can assume, for example, that these were probably suboptimal actions,
我们可以假设，这些行动可能是次优行动，
but it's very possible that these are noisy rewards as well,
但这些也很可能是嘈杂的奖励，
because it's such a sparse signal,
因为它是如此稀少的信号，
it's very possible that you had some good actions at the end
很可能你在最后采取了一些好的行动，
and you were actually trying to recover your car,
你实际上是在试图恢复你的车，
but you were just too late.
但你已经太晚了。
Now repeat this process again,
现在再次重复这个过程，
re-initialize the agent one more time and run it until completion,
再次重新初始化 agent 并运行它，直到完成，
now the agent goes a bit farther, right,
现在 agent 走得更远了一点，
because you've decreased the probabilities at the ends,
因为你已经降低了末端的概率，
increased the probabilities at the future,
增加了未来的概率，
and you keep repeating this over and over again
你不断重复这一过程，
until you notice that the agent learns to perform better and better every time
直到你注意到 agent 每次都学习执行得越来越好，
until it finally converges,
直到它最终收敛，
and at the end, the agent is able to basically follow lanes,
最后， agent 基本上能够沿着车道行驶，
usually swerving a bit side to side while it does that, without crashing,
通常在这样做的过程中会稍微左右转向，而不会撞车，
and this is actually really fascinating,
这真的很有趣，
because this is a self driving car,
因为这是一辆自动驾驶汽车，
that we never taught anything about,
我们从来没有教过任何东西，
what a lane marker means
车道标志是什么意思，
or what are the rules of the road,
或者道路规则是什么，
anything about that, right,
任何这样的东西，
this was a car that learned entirely just by going out,
这是一辆完全通过外出学习的赛车，
crashing a lot and, you know, trying to figure out what to do to not keep doing that in the future.
经常撞车，试图弄清楚如何做才能在未来不再继续这样做。
And the remaining question is actually how we can update, you know, that policy
剩下的问题是我们如何更新策略，
as part of this algorithm that I'm showing you on the right and the left hand side, right,
作为我在左边和右边展示给你们的这个算法的一部分，
like how can we basically formulate that same algorithm,
例如，我们如何才能制定出相同的算法，
and specifically the update equations, steps four and five right here,
具体地说，就是更新方程式，这里第四步和第五步，
these are the two really important steps
这是两个重要的步骤，
of how we can use those two steps to train our policy
我们如何使用这两个步骤来训练我们的策略，
and decrease the probability of bad events,
并降低发生坏事件的可能性，
while promoting these likelihoods of all these good events.
同时促进所有这些好事件的可能性。
So let's assume the, let's look at the loss function,
那么让我们假设，让我们来看看损失函数，
first of all, the loss function for a policy gradient neural network looks like this,
首先，策略梯度神经网络的损失函数是这样的，
and then we'll start by dissecting it
然后我们将从剖析它开始，
to understand why this works the way it does,
以了解为什么它是这样工作的，
so here we can see that the loss consists of two terms,
所以在这里我们可以看到，损失由两项组成，
the first term is this term in green,
第一项是绿色的项，
just called the log likelihood of selecting a particular action,
被称为选择特定行动的对数概率，
the second term is something that all of you are very familiar with already,
第二项是你们都非常熟悉的东西，
this is simply the return at a specific time,
这只是一个特定时间的回报，
so that's the expected return on rewards that you would get after this time point.
所以这是在这个时间点之后你将获得的预期回报。
Now, let's assume that we got a lot of reward for a particular action,
现在，让我们假设我们从特定操作种获得到大量奖励，
that had a high loss probability or high probability,
有高的损失概率，
if we got a lot of reward for a particular action that had high probability,
如果我们从概率很高的特定行动中获得了很多奖励，
that means that we want to increase that probability even further,
这意味着我们想要进一步增加这种可能性，
so we do it even more or even more likelihood,
所以我们做的可能性更大，甚至更有可能，
we sampled that action again into the future.
我们在未来再次采样这种行动。
On the other hand, if we selected
另一方面，如果我们选择，
or let's say if we obtained a reward,
或比方说，如果我们获得的奖励，
that was very low for an action that had high likelihood,
对于一个可能性很高的行动来说是非常低的，
we want the inverse effect,
我们想要相反的效果，
we never want to sample that action again in the future,
我们不想在未来再次尝试这种行为，
because it resulted in a low reward, right,
因为它导致了低回报，
and you'll notice that this loss function right here,
你们会注意到，这个损失函数，
by including this negative,
通过包括这个负值，
we're going to minimize the likelihood of achieving any action that had low rewards in this trajectory,
我们将最小化在这个轨道上实现任何回报较低的行动的可能性，
now in our simplified example on the car example,
现在在我们的简化汽车例子中，
all the things that had low rewards
所有奖励较低的东西，
were exactly those actions that came closest to the termination part of the of the vehicle,
都是那些最接近车辆终止部分的行为，
all the things that had high rewards were the things that came in the beginning,
所有有高回报的东西都是一开始就来的，
that's just the assumption that we make when defining our reward structure.
这只是我们在定义回报结构时所做的假设。
Now we can plug this into the the loss of gradient descent algorithm to train our neural network,
现在我们可以将其插入到损失梯度下降算法中来训练我们的神经网络，
when we see, you know, this policy gradient algorithm,
当我们看到这个策略梯度算法，
which you can see highlighted here,
你可以在这里突出显示，
this gradient is exactly of the policy part of the neural network,
这种梯度恰恰是神经网络的策略部分，
that's the probability of selecting an action,
这是选择一个动作的概率，
even a specific state,
甚至是一个特定的状态，
and if you remember before when we defined,
如果你还记得我们之前定义的，
you know, what does it mean to be a policy function,
作为一个策略函数意味着什么，
that's exactly what it means, right,
这就是它的意思，
given a particular state that you find yourself in,
给定你发现自己所处的特定状态，
what is the probability of selecting a particular action with the highest likelihood,
选择具有最高可能性的特定操作的概率是多少，
and that's, you know, exactly where this method gets its name
这就是这个方法得名的原因，
from this policy gradient piece here that you can see here.
你可以在这里看到这个策略梯度部分。
Now, I want to take maybe just a very brief second towards the end of the class here just to talk about,
现在，我想在这节课快结束的时候花很短的时间来谈谈，
you know, some of the challenges and keeping in line with the first lecture today,
和今天的第一节课保持一致的一些挑战，
some of the challenges of deploying these types of algorithms in the context of the real world, right.
在现实世界中部署这些类型的算法的一些挑战。
What do you think when you look at this training algorithm that you can see here,
当你看到这个训练算法时，你会怎么想，
what do you think are the shortcomings of this training algorithm
你认为这种训练算法的缺点是什么，
and which step, I guess, specifically if we wanted to deploy this approach into reality?
具体是哪一步，如果我们想要将这种方法部署到现实中？
Yeah, exactly, so it's step two, right.
是的，就是这样，所以是第二步。
If you wanted to do this in reality, right,
如果你想在现实中做到这一点，
that essentially means that you want to go out,
那意味着你想出去，
collect your car, crashing it a bunch of times,
取走你的车，把它撞上很多次，
just to learn how to not crash it, right,
就是为了学习如何不撞它，
and that's, you know, that's simply not feasible, right, number one,
第一，而这是根本不可行的，
it's also, you know, very dangerous, number two.
第二，这也是非常危险的。
So there are ways around this, right,
所以有办法绕过这一点，
the number one way around this is that,
绕过这一问题的第一种方法是，
people try to train these types of models in simulation, right,
人们试图在模拟中训练这些类型的模型，
simulation is very safe,
模拟是非常安全的，
because you know we're not going to actually be damaging anything real,
因为我们实际上不会破坏任何真实的东西，
it's still very inefficient,
它的效率仍然很低，
because we have to run these algorithms a bunch of times
因为我们不得不多次运行这些算法，
and crash them a bunch of times,
并多次使它们撞车，
just learn not to crash,
只是学习不要撞车，
but at least now at least from a safety point of view,
但至少现在从安全的角度来看，
it's much safer.
这样安全多了。
But, you know, the problem is that modern simulation engines for reinforcement learning
但是，问题是用于强化学习的现代模拟引擎，
and generally, very broadly speaking, modern simators for vision specifically,
一般来说，特别是视觉的现代模拟器，
do not at all capture reality very accurately,
根本不能非常准确地捕捉到现实，
in fact, there's a very famous notion called the sim-to-real gap,
事实上，有一个非常著名的概念叫做 sim-to-real 鸿沟，
which is a gap that exists,
这是存在的鸿沟，
when you train algorithms in simulation,
当你在模拟中训练算法时，
and they don't extend to
它们不会延伸到，
a lot of the phenomena that we see and the patterns that we see in reality.
我们在现实中看到的许多现象和模式。
And one really cool result that I want to just highlight here is that,
我想在这里强调的一个非常酷的结果是，
when we're training reinforcement learning algorithms,
当我们训练强化学习算法时，
we ultimately want them to be, you know, not operating in simulation,
我们最终希望它们不是在模拟中运行。
we want them to be in reality,
我们希望它们是真实存在的，
and as part of our lab here at MIT,
作为我们 MIT 实验的一部分，
we've been developing this very, very cool brand new photo, realistic simulation engine,
我们一直在开发这种非常、非常酷的全新照片、逼真的模拟引擎，
that goes beyond basically the paradigm of how simulators work today,
它超越了当今模拟器工作的模式，
which is basically defining a model of their environment
基本上就是定义一个环境模型，
and trying to, you know, synthesize that that model,
并试图合成这个模型，
essentially these simulators are like glorified game engines, right,
从本质上讲，这些模拟器就像是美化了的游戏引擎，
they all look very game like, when you look at them,
当你看着他们的时候，他们看起来都很像游戏，
but one thing that we've done is taken a data driven approach
但我们所做的一件事是采用数据驱动的方法，
using real data of the real world,
使用真实世界的真实数据，
can we build up synthetic environments that are super photo realistic and look like this, right,
我们可以建立一个超逼真的合成环境，看起来就像这样，
so this is a cool result that we created here at MIT,
这是我们 MIT 创造的一个很酷的结果，
developing this photo realistic simulation engine,
开发照片真实感模拟引擎时，
this is actually an autonomous agent,
这实际上是一个自动 agent ，
not a real car driving through our virtual simulator
而不是一辆真正的汽车通过我们的虚拟模拟器，
and a bunch of different types of different scenarios,
一堆不同类型的不同场景，
so this simulator is called VISTA,
所以这个模拟器被称为 VISTA ，
allows us to basically use real data that we do collect in the real world,
它允许我们使用我们在真实世界中收集的真实数据，
but then re-simulate those same real roads,
然后重新模拟那些相同的真实道路，
so for example, let's say you take your car,
例如，假设你开着你的车，
you drive out on [mass have], you collect data of [mass have],
开着[质量]的车，收集[质量]数据，
you can now drop a virtual agent into that same simulated environment,
现在你可以把一个虚拟 agent 放到同一个模拟环境中，
observing new viewpoints of what that scene might have looked like
观察那个场景可能是什么样子的新视角，
from different types of perturbations
从不同类型的扰动，
or, or types of angles that it might be exposed to.
或它可能暴露的角度。
And that allows us to train these agents now entirely using reinforcement learning,
这允许我们完全使用强化学习来训练这些 agent ，
no human labels,
没有人类的标签，
but importantly allowed them to be transferred into reality,
但重要的是允许它们转移到现实中，
because there's no sim-to-real gap anymore.
因为不再有 sim-to-real 鸿沟。
So in fact, we did exactly this,
所以事实上，我们就是这么做的，
we placed agents into our simulator,
我们将 agent 放入我们的模拟器中，
we trained them using the exact algorithms,
我们使用确切的算法，
that you learned about in today's lecture these policy gradient algorithms
你们在今天的课程中学到的策略梯度算法，
and all of the training was done entirely in simulation,
所有的训练都完全在模拟中完成，
then we took these policies
然后我们采取了这些策略，
and we deployed them on board our full scale autonomous vehicle,
并将它们部署在我们的全尺寸自动驾驶汽车上，
this is now in the real world, no longer in simulation,
这现在是在真实世界中，不再是在模拟中，
and on the left hand side you can see,
在左边你可以看到，
basically this car driving through this environment completely autonomous in the real world,
基本上这辆车在现实世界中完全自主地通过这个环境，
no transfer learning is is done here,
没有迁移学习在这里做，
there is no augmentation of data from real world data,
不存在从真实世界数据中增加数据的情况，
this is entirely trained using simulation
这完全是使用模拟来训练的，
and this represented actually the first time ever,
这是有史以来第一次，
that reinforcement learning was used to train a policy end to end,
使用强化学习来端到端地训练策略，
we're an autonomous vehicle that could be deployed in reality,
我们是一辆可以在现实中部署的自动驾驶汽车，
so that was something really cool that we we created here at MIT.
这是我们在 MIT 创造的很酷的东西。
But now that we covered, you know, all of these foundations of reinforcement learning and policy learning,
但现在我们已经讨论了强化学习和策略学习的所有基础，
I want to touch on some other maybe very exciting applications that we're seeing,
我想谈谈我们正在看到的其他一些可能非常令人兴奋的应用，
and one very popular application,
一个受欢迎的应用，
that a lot of people will tell you about and talk about is the game of Go.
很多人都会告诉你和谈论它的游戏是围棋。
So here reinforcement learning agents could be
所以在这里，强化学习 agent 可以用来，
actually tried to put against the test against you know, grand master level Go players
对抗围棋大师级别的棋手的测试，
and you know at the time achieved incredibly impressive results,
当时取得了令人难以置信的令人印象深刻的结果，
so for those of you who are not familiar with the game of Go,
所以，对于那些不熟悉围棋游戏的人来说，
Go, game of Go is played on a 19 by 19 board,
围棋是在 19x19 的棋盘上玩的，
the rough objective of Go is
围棋的粗略目标是，
to claim basically more board pieces than your opponent, right,
比你的对手拥有更多的棋子，
and through the grid of, sorry through the grid,
通过这个网格，
that you can see here this 19 by 19 grid,
你可以在这里看到这个 19x19 的网格，
and while the game itself, the the logical rules, are actually quite simple,
虽然游戏本身，逻辑规则，实际上非常简单，
the number of possible action spaces and possible states that this board
但这块棋盘可以放置的可能行动空间和可能状态的数量
could be placed into is greater than the number of atoms in the universe,
比宇宙中的原子数量更多，
so this game, even though the rules are very simple in their logical definitions,
因此，这个游戏，尽管规则在逻辑定义上非常简单，
is an extraordinarily complex game for an artificial algorithm to try and master.
但对于一个人工算法来说，它是一个非常复杂的游戏。
So the objective here was to build a reinforcement learning algorithm to master the game of Go,
所以这里的目标是建立一种强化学习算法来掌握围棋游戏，
not only beating, you know, these gold standard softwareares,
不仅击败这些黄金标准软件，
but also what was at the time like an amazing result was to beat the grand master level players,
而且在当时看起来像是一个惊人的结果是击败了大师级的棋手，
so the number one player in the world of Go was a human human champion, obviously.
围棋世界排名第一的棋手显然是人类冠军。
So Google DeepMind rose to this challenge,
所以 Google DeepMind 应对了这个挑战，
they created a couple years ago developing this solution,
他们几年前开发了这个解决方案，
which is very much based in the exact same algorithms that you learned about in today's lecture,
它非常基于你们在今天的课程中学到的完全相同的算法，
combining both the value part of this network with [residual] layers,
将这个网络的价值部分和[残留]层结合在一起，
which we'll cover in the next lecture tomorrow,
我们将在明天的下一节课中讨论，
and using reinforcement learning pipeline,
而使用强化学习管道，
they were able to defeat the grand champion human players
他们能够击败人类玩家的大冠军，
and the idea that its core was actually very simple,
而其核心的想法其实很简单，
the first step is that you train a neural network
第一步是你训练一个神经网络，
to basically watch human level experts,
基本上观看人类水平的专家，
so this is not using reinforcement learning, using supervised learning,
所以这不是使用强化学习，使用监督学习，
using the techniques that we covered in lectures one, two and three.
使用我们在第一课、第二课和第三课中讨论的技术。
And from this first step,
从第一步开始，
the goal is to build like a policy,
我们的目标是建立一个类似于一个策略，
that would imitate some of the rough patterns that a human type of player
它将模仿人类玩家，
or a human grandmaster would take,
或人类特级大师采取的，
based on a given board state, the type of actions that they might execute,
根据给定的棋盘，他们可能采取的行动，
but then given this pre trained model,
但给出这个预先训练的模型，
essentially you could use it to bootstrap and reinforcement learning algorithm,
你可以用它来引导和强化学习算法，
that would play against itself,
这将与它自己的竞争，
in order to learn how to improve even beyond the human levels, right,
为了学习如何超越人类的水平来提高，
so it would take its human understandings,
所以，它需要人类的理解，
try to imitate the humans first of all,
首先试图模仿人类，
but then from that imitation,
但通过这种模仿，
they would pin these two neural networks against themselves,
它们会将这两个神经网络与他们自己联系起来，
play a game against themselves
与他们自己玩游戏，
and the winners would be receiving a reward,
获胜者将获得奖励，
the losers would try to negate all of the actions that they may have acquired from their human counterparts
失败者会试图否定他们可能从人类同行那里获得的所有行动，
and try to actually learn new types of rules and new types of actions
并试图实际学习新类型的规则和新类型的行动，
basically that might be very beneficial to achieving superhuman performance.
可能对实现超人表现非常有益。
And one of the very important auxiliary tricks that brought this idea to be possible was,
使这个想法成为可能的一个非常重要的辅助技巧是，
the usage of this second network,
使用第二个网络，
this auxiliary network which took as input the state of the board
这个辅助网络将棋盘的状态作为输入，
and tried to predict, you know, what are all of the different possible board states that might emerge from this particular state
并试图预测，从这个特定的状态可能出现的所有不同的棋盘状态，
and what would their values be,
它们的值是什么，
what would their potential returns and their outcomes be,
他们的潜在回报和结果会是什么，
so this network was an auxiliary network,
所以这个网络是一个辅助网络，
that was almost hallucinating, right,
几乎是幻觉，
different board states that it could take from this particular state
不同的棋盘状态，它可以从这个特定的状态中采取行动，
and using those predicted values to guide its planning of,
并使用这些预测值来指导它的规划，
you know, what action should it take into the future.
它应该在未来采取什么行动。
And finally, very much more recently,
最后，就在最近，
they extended this algorithm
他们扩展了这个算法，
and showed that they could not even use the human grand masters in the beginning to imitate from in the beginning,
表明它们甚至不能从一开始就使用人类大师来模仿，
and bootstrap these algorithms,
引导这些算法，
what if they just started entirely from scratch
如果他们只是完全从头开始，
and just had two neural networks never trained before,
只有两个从未训练过的神经网络，
they start pinning themselves against each other
然后他们开始相互依附，
and you could actually see that,
你实际上可以看到，
you could without any human supervision at all,
你可以在没有任何人类监督的情况下，
have a neural network, learn to not only outperform the solution that outperform the humans,
让神经网络学习不仅要超越超越人类的解决方案，
but also outperform the solution that was created,
而且还要超越人类创造的解决方案，
which was bootstrapped by humans as well.
后者也是由人类引导的。
So with that, I'll summarize very quickly what we've learned today
到此为止，我将非常快速地总结我们今天所学的内容，
and and conclude for the day.
并结束这一天。
So we've talked a lot about really the foundational algorithms underlying reinforcement learning,
所以我们已经讨论了很多关于强化学习的基本算法，
we saw two different types of reinforcement learning approaches
我们看到了两种不同类型的强化学习方法，
of how we can optimize these solutions,
来优化这些解决方案，
first being Q-learning,
首先是 Q 学习，
where we're trying to actually estimate,
我们试图实际估计，
given a state, you know,
给定一个状态，
what is the value that we might expect for any possible action,
我们可能期望的任何可能的行动的值是什么，
in the second way was to take a much more end to end approach
第二种方式是采取更端到端的方法，
and say how, given the state that we see ourselves in,
并说，考虑到我们所处的状态，
what is the likelihood, that I should take any given action
我应该采取任何给定行动，
to maximize the potential that I I have in this particular state.
来最大化我在这种特定状态下的潜力。
And I hope that all of this was very exciting to you,
我希望所有的这些对你们来说都非常令人兴奋，
today we have a very exciting lab
我们有一个非常令人兴奋的实验，
and kick off for the competition
竞赛开始了，
and the deadline for these competitions will be,
竞赛的最后期限会是，
well, it was originally set to be thursday,
原定是星期四，
which is tomorrow at 11pm.
也就是明天晚上 11 点。
Thank you.
谢谢。